

COMPUTER SCIENCE INSTRUCTOR

Details

New Caney, United States (909) 906-3087 landmarkist@gmail.com

Skills

Strong analytical skills Proficient in data analysis tools (e.g. Excel, SQL, BI)

Experience coding in Java, R, C#, C++, Python.

Experience with process mapping and workflow design.

Excellent project management skills.

Strong communication and collaboration skills.

Familiarity with Agile development methodologies.

Profile

Highly skilled and experienced computer science instructor with a proven track record of success in teaching and mentoring students of all ages and skill levels. Well-versed in a wide range of programming languages, software development methodologies, and computer science concepts. Strong ability to effectively communicate complex technical concepts to both technical and non-technical audiences. Proven ability to stay current with the latest developments and trends in the computer science field.

Employment History

Adjunct Computer Science Instructor at San Jacinto College, Houston, TX

AUGUST 2023 — PRESENT

- Taught introductory computer science courses (COSC1436 and COSC1437).
- Instructed students in Java and C++.

Computer Science Instructor at Sheldon ISD, Houston, TX

AUGUST 2016 — PRESENT

- Awarded for increasing diversity, equity, and inclusion in the field of computer science.
- Instilled a passion in my classes for data structures, algorithms, and programming design.
- Instructed students in Java, C#, and Python coding languages.

Inventory Analyst at Dorel Juvenile Group, Ontario, CA

MARCH 2015 — AUGUST 2016

- Slashed year end monthly labor costs by 10% through the development of a system that automated year-end inventories.
- Achieved a 15% reduction in lead time by developing a more meaningful process for SKUs and inventory locating systems.
- Performed thorough research and documentation of inventory discrepancies to identify root causes and provide solutions.
- Collaborated with key stakeholders from Shipping to resolve any operational concerns or gaps in processes related to inventory.

Inventory Control Analyst at Bolthouse Farms, Bakersfield, CA

APRIL 2007 — OCTOBER 2013

- Supported senior management by creating software to report inventory control data, KPIs, and overall equipment efficiencies.
- Minimized process discrepancies by spearheading more efficient methods of production, storage, and shipping.

Education

PhD Leadership, Carolina University, Winston-Salem, NC

JULY 2010 — AUGUST 2020

Graduated with high distinction.

MS in Applied Computer Science, Frostburg State University, Frostburg, MD

BS in Business Administration, Colorado Christian University, Lakewood, CO

MAY 2007 — MAY 2009

Graduated with University Honors